GREGOR KICZALES: In this video, I'm just going
to go through some of the basic terminology and rules in Sudoku.
So this is really kind of like a domain analysis for the problem
we're about to solve.
So first, Sudoku is played on a nine by nine board.
Because it's nine by nine, the board has 81 of what we're going to call,
squares.
In addition to the 81 squares, we say that the board has nine rows,
because it's a nine by nine board, nine columns,
because it's a nine by nine board, and it also has nine boxes.
Where the boxes are, are little three by three blocks of the whole board.
And so there's three boxes at the top, three boxes kind of in the middle,
and three boxes at the bottom.
So the rows, the columns, and the boxes together comprise what are called,
units.
There's 27 total units, because there's nine rows, nine columns, and nine
boxes.
And adding nine, nine, and nine gets 27.
So there's 27 total units, and now we have enough terminology
to concisely say the goal of the game.
The goal of the game is to fill every square with a natural number from one
to nine but making sure that there's not a duplicate number in any unit.
So there can't be a single row that has a duplicate number in it.
There can't be a single column that has a duplicate number in it.
And there can't be a single box that has a duplicate number it.
Because we have the term unit, we can say that more concisely
as there can't be a single unit that has a duplicate number in it.
So just to be clear, this is an illegal move.
You can't put a six in that third box in the first row,
because there's already a six in that row.
So that's an illegal move.
Here's another illegal move.
You can't put a one there, because there's already a one in that column.
So that's an illegal move.
And here's another illegal move.
You can't put a three there.
You can't put the red three in, because there's already a three in that box.
That's an illegal move.
Again, the goal of the game is to fill in every square
with a natural from one to nine inclusive but making sure that there's
not a duplicate number in any unit.
So that's the quick terminology of Sudoku and quick summary of the rules.
Again, if you've never seen Sudoku before,
and you'd like a bit more detailed introduction to the rules of the game,
just do a web search and find one of the many Sudoku sites.
And you could play one or two quick games before picking up the next video.